<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<title>House</title>
	<subtitle>Watch as I bludgeon a house into a home</subtitle>
	
	<link href="https://joshuajenkins.com/house/feed/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="https://joshuajenkins.com/house/"/>
	<updated>2020-12-29T16:00:00-08:00</updated>
	<id>https://joshuajenkins.com/house/</id>
	<author>
		<name>Joshua Jenkins</name>
		<email></email>
	</author>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Pre-closure</title>
		<link href="https://joshuajenkins.com/house/posts/2020-12-30/"/>
		<updated>2020-12-29T16:00:00-08:00</updated>
		<id>https://joshuajenkins.com/house/posts/2020-12-30/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve always wanted to live in New York. So, I bought a house in San Francisco, my home for the past ten years. I feel that it&#39;s time to put down some roots and give my demons a little more space to stretch out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow, I close on the house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am confident of two things going into this. One, this house will be going through changes, baby. Two, I&#39;m going to struggle with nearly all of it. Maybe I&#39;ll learn something along the way. Maybe it&#39;ll break me. Maybe I&#39;ll break the house. Who knows, but I might as well write some of it down. Think of this as the diary of a house in metamorphosis, but keep in mind that this is really about meeeeeeeeeeeee!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The odd stretch of time between seeing the house, through making an offer, to daydreaming and stressing before it closes has left my poor feeble mind flooded with thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I generously unburden myself of these surely naïve thoughts in stream of consciouness form now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I called the house &amp;quot;special&amp;quot; to multiple parties that have a financial interest in my believing this. The house may not be special.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In fact, it is probably a good example of one of the less special relatively intact Victorians in San Francisco.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The house was built in 1901! Before the 1906 earthquake and subsequent fires, and now that I think about it, it even predates my birth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frustratingly, I&#39;m closing on the house on the last day of 2020, so I have to awkwardly call it a one hundred nineteen year old house for part of a day before mercifully transitioning into calling it a one hundred twenty year old house for a blissful year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The house accumulated a series of structurally dubious, aesthetically really-dubious, and seemingly illegal modifications over the years (decades? centuries!!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The house appears to be sprinkled with semi-permanent sentimental artifacts that I anticipate will let out tiny little screams as I slowly dislodge them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I feel little about Victorians other than an appreciation for their high ceilings. The obsession with ornamentation, no matter how half- to quarter-assed, is simply not my thing. And this house has a lot of quarter-assed detailing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The house is in need of upgrades, modern comforts, structural repairs, and a tickle or two.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It has a big back yard with lots of mature trees. I trust that my guaranteed lack of active effort in identifying and subsequently caring for these trees will generate a cosmic imbalance that will result in a furious arborist arriving on my (newfound emphasis on &amp;quot;my,&amp;quot; here) doorstep, instigating a wonderful, decades-long frienship.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a big, leaking hot tub on the back deck. Early opinions are split—some think that a bit of chlorine will render it nonradioactive, while others posit that it may be full of something other than water and the best course of action may be to take a chainsaw to it. Franklin Covey calls this a &amp;quot;win-win&amp;quot;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is also a small greenhouse that contains, per the listing description, &amp;quot;rare offerings&amp;quot;. I&#39;m not qualified to confirm or object to this description, but the two dead-ish looking plants within seem like they could have suffered equally with less effort.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Certain windows, if scowled through, reveal a bit of a view of the taller structures in the Mission (e.g. the baroque domed tower of Mission High School) as well as a view of some of the beloathed recent additions to the downtown skyline, which I mostly don&#39;t mind.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I intend to find a way to ehance these slight views because I will forever question why I didn&#39;t buy a house on one of San Francisco&#39;s nine hundred and fifty-three hills, five of which start within fourteen inches of my front door, all of which sport, in realtor parlance, killer views, bro.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The block it&#39;s on is a big question mark for me. A semi-quiet in-between block flanked by a string of gay bars, a bus line, a gas station, and a subway stop. Likely in the urban splash zone, but to what degree remains to be seen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The back of the house belongs to me, insofar as I may be able to take some liberties with modifications. This is good because the backside is, in my current opinion, not wholly taking advantage of the blessed rays of light that shine down upon it. Some basking has been left on the table.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The front of the house belongs, effectively, to the fragile public of 1901. It looks old so I can&#39;t really mess with it, because famously progressive San Francisco is, in fact, quite conservative.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;San Francisco has arcane, draconian, other-fun-words but mostly just hugely restrictive and crushingly beauracratic processes for modifying historic properties, which unfortunately this house technically is (historic, property), by a hair, and I very much intend on modifying this sucker.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ll look back on this and laugh.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
