<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<title>House</title>
	<subtitle>Watch as I bludgeon a house into a home</subtitle>
	
	<link href="https://joshuajenkins.com/house/feed/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="https://joshuajenkins.com/house/"/>
	<updated>2020-12-29T16:00:00-08:00</updated>
	<id>https://joshuajenkins.com/house/</id>
	<author>
		<name>Joshua Jenkins</name>
		<email></email>
	</author>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Pre-closure</title>
		<link href="https://joshuajenkins.com/house/posts/2020-12-30/"/>
		<updated>2020-12-29T16:00:00-08:00</updated>
		<id>https://joshuajenkins.com/house/posts/2020-12-30/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow I close on my first house. In future retrospect it may be obvious that the house, in fact, closed on me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am confident of two things going into this. One, this house will be going through changes, baby. Two, probably I will too. At the onset it&#39;s not immediately obvious that either party is going to come out of this better than where they started, but I guarantee both of us have some dumb shit burried in our walls that will be entertaining to put on display.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So think of this as the diary of a house in metamorphosis, but keep in mind that this is really about meeeeeeeeeeeee!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some initial thoughts I am writing down for the express purpose of generating feelings of personal embarassment in the future:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I called the house &amp;quot;special&amp;quot; to multiple parties that have a financial interest in my believing this. The house may not be special.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In fact, it is probably a good example of one of the less-special relatively intact Victorians in San Francisco. Plenty more on this in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The house was built in 1901! Before the 1906 earthquake and subsequent fires, and now that I think about it, it even predates my birth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frustratingly, I&#39;m closing on the house on the last day of 2020, so I have to awkwardly call it a one hundred nineteen year old house for part of a day before mercifully transitioning into calling it a one hundred twenty year old house for a blissful year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The house accumulated a series of structurally dubious, aesthetically really-dubious, and seemingly illegal modifications over the years (decades? centuries!!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lives were lived in this house. Oh, if the walls could talk! Sincerely, I hope that they cannot or at least will not.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The house appears filled with what I will call semi-permanent sentimental artifacts that I anticipate will let out tiny little screams as I slowly dislodge them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is a good moment to note that I feel nothing about Victorians other than an appreciation for their high ceilings. The prescriptive use of space with all its attendant opinions on how to live coupled with the obsession with artiface, no matter how half- to quarter-assed, are simply not my thing. A little taste of the battles to come.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The house is need of upgrades, modern comforts, structural repairs, and a tickle or two.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It has a big back yard. With lots of mature trees. I trust that my guaranteed lack of active effort in identifying and subsequently caring for these trees (e.g. my property that I can neglect for private and public benefit) will generate a cosmic imbalance that will result in a furious arborist arriving on my (newfound emphasis on &amp;quot;my,&amp;quot; here) doorstep, instigating a wonderful, decades-long frienship.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a big, leaking hot tub on the back deck. Early opinions are split—some think that a bit of chlorine will render it non-radioactive, while others posit that it may be full of something other than water and the best course of action may be to take a chainsaw to it. Franklin Covey calls this a &amp;quot;win-win&amp;quot;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Certain windows, if scowled through, reveal a bit of a view of the taller structures in the Mission (e.g. the baroque domed tower of Mission High School) as well as a view of some of the beloathed recent additions to the downtown skyline.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I intend to find a way to ehance these slight views because I will forever question why I didn&#39;t buy a house on one of San Francisco&#39;s nine hundred and fifty-three hills, five of which start within fourteen inches of my front door.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Relatedly, I suspect that significantly more rays of light could strike the floors and walls of the interior of this house at certain times of day than currnently do, at least on the back side, which is legally allowed to react to the current millenium, unlike the front, which belongs to the adoring and fragile public of 1901. There are no sides. This is San Francisco.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The house is either on a really good block, a really bad block, or a block with positive and negative elements like any other.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;San Francisco has arcane, draconian, other-fun-words but mostly just hugely restrictive and crushingly beauracratic processes for modifying historic properties, which unfortunately this house technically is (historic, property), by a hair, and I very much intend on modifying this sucker.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of an abundance of caution that 2020 may not be documented in the historical record, I am doing my part to make sure this year is remembered through my selfless act of purchasing a home and going to great lengths to describe how interesting it is.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
